So, I'm here with Robert from Airbnb.
今天 我们邀请到了 Airbnb 的 Robert
Robert, thanks so much for joining us.
Robert 非常感谢接受我们的邀请
Thank you for having me.
感谢邀请
So, I know that you have actually quite a few posts on Medium
我知道你在 Medium 上发表过很多文章
that have a lot of people who read them and follow your work,
有很多的人阅读你的文章 并且关注你的作品
can you talk about how you got started with that?
你能跟我们谈一谈当初你是如何开始做这件事吗
What are some of the ways that you go about sharing your information? Things like that.
比如你有哪些分享信息的方式之类的
So, I wrote my first public posts in 2015,
我在 2015 年的时候发表了我的第一篇文章
and it was about my experience working as a data scientist at Twitter,
有关我在 Twitter 做数据科学家的经验
and it was meant to be a reflection of my journey for myself,
它原本是我关于自己工作的一个反思和总结
but then eventually it got retweeted by a famous data scientists,
但它后来被一个很有名的数据科学家在 Twitter 给转发了
and then it went viral, unexpectedly.
所以就被很快地传播来开
I think that gave me some courage to keep writing,
我想 这件事情给了我继续写下去的勇气
and what I've noticed so far in all my pursuit in writing
我还发现 我写作的有关数据科学的内容
about data science is I generally write about subjects
其实都是自己曾经花费了很大力气
that I struggled to learn in the past.
去学习的东西
For example, I am very passionate about data engineering,
比如 我对数据工程有非常大的热情
but few years back,
但在几年前
it's very hard for me to find useful information,
网络上有关这个领域的信息非常少
but then I am very fortunate to work at Airbnb,
后来我非常有幸地来到了Airbnb工作
work with many very smart data engineers,
和那些非常聪明的数据工程师们共事
and I've learned a lot from them.
并从他们身上学到了很多东西
So, I decided to just synthesize and write down everything that I know about the subject.
所以我决定把我知道的关于数据工程的一切都总结和记录下来
One is to for me,
一方面是为了我自己更好地内化这些知识
for myself internalize what I've learned and to celebrate it a little bit,
也小小地庆祝一下
and then the second part is just to make information more available to other people.
另外一方面也是想把信息分享给他人
Yeah, I think Holly Wicham had a quote, not a quote sorry,
Holly Wicham 曾经在 Twitter 上说过一句话
had a tweet which he said things are useful,
很多事情都是有价值的
doesn't have to just be a complete new software, sometimes it's documentation.
不一定非要创造出一个全新的软件 软件的文档也有价值
Sometimes there's just explaining how things work.
解释一个事情如何运作这件事本身同样具有价值
I really echo with that,
我非常赞同他的观点
because I really benefit a lot from people who can explain things really well,
因为我真的从那些能把事情解释和表达地非常清楚
and who can articulate things really well to me so that I can learn this stuff.
的人身上受益良多
Then you do it to a whole broad audience.
写作只是把受众的群体扩大了而已
Yeah, I hope I contribute a little bit to that, yeah.
所以我希望 在这方面 我有做一点点的贡献
So, do you have any advice for people who are
对于那些刚开始准备写文章的人
just getting started with writing their own post?
你有什么经验可以分享的吗？
There's a lot of benefits of putting your work out there,
分享自己的知识和经验有很多的好处
because you will get unexpected feedback and sometimes you will get
因为你会得到很多意想不到的反馈
unexpected attention or opportunities.
或者意料之外的机会和关注
So, I think this is true if you're early in your career,
这对于刚开始工作或者
or your had been in industry for a few years.
已经工作了几年的人都有帮助
Just sharing stuff in general I think it's really valuable,
分享本身就是一件很有价值的事情
and it's something that's generally,
我想这也是硅谷
I think that's something that's quite special about Tech in Silicon Valley in general,
非常有魅力的地方
just like people are very willing to share information,
有很多愿意分享 并具有分享精神的人
and there's a lot of benefits from that.
分享有非常多的好处